<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://klrshak.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://klrshak.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-05-24T17:40:41+00:00</updated><id>https://klrshak.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Shaurya K. Panwar</title><subtitle>Shaurya Kishore Panwar&apos;s personal website. Collection of personal and professional work and experiences through my career. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Starters Kit for Plein-Air Painting</title><link href="https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2025/plein-air-starters-kit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starters Kit for Plein-Air Painting"/><published>2025-05-20T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-20T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2025/plein-air-starters-kit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2025/plein-air-starters-kit/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="a-beginners-guide-to-getting-started-with-plein-air-painting">A Beginner’s guide to getting started with Plein-Air Painting</h1> <p>Whether you dream of capturing sunrise over the lake or just want an excuse to spend more time outdoors, plein-air painting is a rewarding way to sharpen your eye and enjoy nature. Below you’ll find a <strong>starter materials list</strong> (split into <strong>watercolor</strong> and <strong>acrylic</strong> kits) followed by practical advice on setup, workflow, and staying comfortable outside.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="1-the-minimalist-supply-lists">1. The Minimalist Supply Lists</h2> <p>Below you’ll find some reccomendation of the materials/stuff that you might need, these are reccommendations feel free to make the setup for yourself</p> <h3 id="watercolor-kit">Watercolor Kit</h3> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Item</th> <th>Why It Matters</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td><strong>Travel-size watercolor set</strong> (12 shades or more half-pans or Tubes)</td> <td>I reccomend pre-filled pans let you paint straight by just mixing a little water. You can also try out tubes if you like.</td> </tr> <tr> <td>**Watercolor Paper Pad **</td> <td>300 gsm (140 lb) paper resists warping—spiral pads stay flat in wind.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Three or more versatile brushes</strong></td> <td>#8 round (general), #4 round (detail), ¾″ flat (washes). Synthetic is fine.(a big, medium and fine)</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Lightweight folding palette</strong></td> <td>Extra mixing space if the box lid feels cramped.(You can have a palette with different wells or compartments for different colors)</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>water cup(Mug) + small spray bottle</strong></td> <td>Spray keeps mixes moist; a cup or mug of water to wash brushes.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Mechanical pencil &amp; kneaded eraser</strong></td> <td>Clean, erasable lines that won’t smudge under washes.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Absorbent cloth or paper towel</strong></td> <td>Controls moisture and blotting. General cleaning</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Binder clip &amp; masking tape</strong></td> <td>Keep pages still on breezy days.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>Recommendations Winsor and Newton beginner’s bundle: https://eu.winsornewton.com/collections/beginner-watercolour-sets/products/cotman-watercolour-beginners-bundle</p> <h3 id="acrylic-or-gouache-kit">Acrylic (or Gouache) Kit</h3> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Item</th> <th>Why It Matters</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td><strong>Acrylic Paints - 6 or more shades</strong></td> <td>Any beginner kit that comes with 6 or more shades. I reccommend the paint that comes in tube instead of in a bottle</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>A palette</strong></td> <td>A tear-off palette or flat plastic palette. (I don’t recommend against a palette with different compartments)</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>At-least Three or more versatile brushes</strong></td> <td>½″ bright (blocking), #6 filbert (general), #2 round (detail). Synthetic Taklon handles acrylic well.(a big, medium and fine)</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Pre-primed canvas panels / acrylic paper pad</strong></td> <td>9 × 12 in or smaller; rigid panels slot easily into a backpack.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Atomizer bottle &amp; retarder medium</strong></td> <td>A quick mist or retarder drop keeps paint workable in dry air.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Water Cup or Mug</strong> for water</td> <td>Rinse brushes and thin mixes.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Compact field easel</strong> (optional)</td> <td>Aluminium tripod or French half-box; many weigh &lt; 1.5 kg.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Paper towels &amp; zip-bag for dirty rags</strong></td> <td>General cleaning, Acrylic won’t come out of clothes once dry—contain the mess early!</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>Recommendations Winsor and Newton beginner’s bundle: https://eu.winsornewton.com/collections/acrylic-sets/products/galeria-acrylic-galeria-complete-set</p> <blockquote> <p><strong>Budget tip:</strong> Start with student-grade paints plus one good brush; upgrade items as you learn what you truly need.</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h2 id="2-pack-smart-the-5-minute-pre-flight-check">2. Pack Smart: The 5-Minute Pre-Flight Check</h2> <ol> <li><strong>Weather scan</strong> – cloud cover, wind speed, temperature = drying speed.</li> <li><strong>Sun angle</strong> – paint with the sun at your <em>side</em>, not in your eyes or on your surface.</li> <li><strong>Essentials pouch</strong> – phone, mini first-aid kit, snacks, water, SPF, hat.</li> <li><strong>Comfort kit</strong> – lightweight stool, fingerless gloves, insect spray.</li> <li><strong>Leave-no-trace plan</strong> – spare bag for trash, corked jar to transport rinse water home.</li> </ol> <hr/> <h2 id="3-choose-and-simplify-your-subject">3. Choose (and Simplify) Your Subject</h2> <ul> <li>Look for <strong>large, distinct shapes</strong> (bold tree silhouette, bright boat).</li> <li>Squint—what vanishes becomes background tone; don’t chase every twig.</li> <li>Establish a <strong>focal point</strong> <em>before</em> mixing: where should viewers look first?</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="4-field-workflow-in-six-steps">4. Field Workflow in Six Steps</h2> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Step</th> <th>Watercolor</th> <th>Acrylic</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td><strong>1 — Light sketch</strong></td> <td>Pencil contour, no shading.</td> <td>Same, or draw directly with thinned burnt umber.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>2 — Tone block-in</strong></td> <td>Big, light washes (sky, water).</td> <td>Thinned paint covers large masses.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>3 — Mid-value shapes</strong></td> <td>Work background → foreground, save whites.</td> <td>Increase opacity; set main color families.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>4 — Shadows &amp; accents</strong></td> <td>Drop darker pigments into damp areas for soft edges.</td> <td>Thicker paint; palette knife for texture.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>5 — Highlights / details</strong></td> <td>Dry-brush sparkle or opaque gouache touches last.</td> <td>Final high-value strokes (pure titanium white mixes).</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>6 — Evaluate</strong></td> <td>Step back 2 m, check edges &amp; contrasts.</td> <td>Same—fresh eyes catch balance issues.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <hr/> <h2 id="5-quick-color-mixing-essentials">5. Quick Color-Mixing Essentials</h2> <ol> <li><strong>Work light to dark.</strong> In both watercolor and acrylic, it’s easier to deepen a hue than to pull it back once it’s too dark.</li> <li><strong>Limit your palette.</strong> A <strong>split-primary set</strong> (warm + cool version of each primary) keeps mixtures clean: <ul> <li>Warm yellow (e.g., Yellow Ochre) • Cool yellow (Hansa)</li> <li>Warm red (Cadmium Scarlet) • Cool red (Alizarin)</li> <li>Warm blue (Ultramarine) • Cool blue (Phthalo)</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Mix on the palette, tweak on the paper.</strong> Aim for the target colour in the well or mixing area; fine-tune temperature with tiny on-surface touches.</li> <li><strong>Neutral grays = complements.</strong> Mix any colour with its opposite on the wheel (e.g., Ultramarine + Burnt Sienna) for natural shadow grays.</li> <li><strong>Puddle progression.</strong> Start with a large puddle of the dominant sky/water tone—every later mix can borrow from it, keeping the painting harmonious.</li> <li><strong>Test swatches.</strong> Dab a corner of the mix on the page margin before committing. It saves surprises in value or saturation.</li> <li><strong>Record your favourites.</strong> In a spare sketchbook page, note “2 parts Phthalo Blue + 1 part Burnt Umber = Deep Pine Green.” It’s a personal recipe book you’ll reference outdoors.</li> </ol> <blockquote> <p><strong>Quick exercise:</strong> Paint a ten-step gradient strip from pure Ultramarine to pure Burnt Sienna. You’ll discover at step 5 the perfect neutral for distant hills—and you’ll never drag black out of the tube again!</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h2 id="6-common-outdoor-challenges-and-quick-fixes">6. Common Outdoor Challenges (and Quick Fixes)</h2> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Challenge</th> <th>Fix</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td><strong>Changing light</strong></td> <td>Snap a reference photo on arrival; lock in shadows early.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Curious passers-by</strong></td> <td>Earbuds + friendly “Still a work-in-progress” keeps focus.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Paint drying too fast</strong></td> <td>Mist palette for watercolors; spray palette &amp; use retarder for acrylics.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Overworking</strong></td> <td>Limit session to ~90 min; set a timer to force fresh starts.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <hr/> <h3 id="final-word">Final Word</h3> <p>The joy of plein-air isn’t a perfect postcard on the first try—it’s noticing bird calls, shifting clouds, and light you’d miss indoors. Pack light, keep sessions short, and treat every field sketch as a learning snapshot. With each outing you’ll paint faster, see color more clearly, and feel right at home under the sky.</p> <p><strong>Happy painting—see you out there!</strong></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/art/1-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/art/1-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/art/1-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/art/1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/art/7-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/art/7-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/art/7-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/art/7.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/art/8-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/art/8-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/art/8-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/art/8.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Some of my Plein-air paintings, just to show-off :wink: hahaha </div> <p><strong>Signing off…</strong></p> <h5 id="shaurya-shak">Shaurya (ShaK)</h5>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="artwork"/><category term="art"/><category term="paintings"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Beginner's guide to getting started with Plein-Air Painting]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer Of &apos;69 ’23</title><link href="https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2023/summer-23-intern/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer Of &apos;69 ’23"/><published>2023-08-29T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-29T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2023/summer-23-intern</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2023/summer-23-intern/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="drone-dreams-and-swiss-cheese-schemes---my-alpine-internship-adventures">Drone Dreams and Swiss Cheese Schemes - My Alpine Internship Adventures</h2> <p>The summer of 2023 marked a pivotal moment in my life as I embarked on an extraordinary journey to Switzerland. My destination: the Computer Perception and Vision Laboratory (CPVR) at Bern University of Applied Sciences, where I would spend my next three transformative months working on the project “No GPS Drone Project” under the guidance of Prof. Marcus Hudritsch. This project aimed to revolutionize drone navigation by developing a purely vision-based system capable of operating in GPS-denied areas and harsh weather conditions.</p> <p>My adventure began with a 5000-kilometer journey from Delhi, India, to Bern, Switzerland. As a final year student at Delhi Technological University, this was my first international experience, and the thrill was palpable. However, one of the initial pleasant surprises was the European summer sunsets, stretching well past 10 PM. Accustomed to the early sunsets of my tropical homeland, this newfound daylight left an indelible mark on my daily routine in my journey. One of my new favourite past times will be exploring the city on my bicycle after work or going for a swim in the lake.</p> <p>The active Swiss lifestyle was soon apparent, especially with my workplace nestled in the foothills of the Jura mountains, requiring a daily uphill hike. Yet, the breathtaking aerial views of the city made every ascent worthwhile. Upon arrival, I was warmly welcomed into a diverse research group, comprising individuals from various corners of the world, all contributing to a vibrant, multicultural environment. Switzerland’s unique linguistic landscape, with my city having both French and German as official languages named Biel/Bienne, added another layer of cultural richness to my experience.</p> <p>My role as an applied research intern commenced with an extensive review of existing work, involving the meticulous examination of over 3000+ lines of code. Thankfully, my colleagues demonstrated exceptional patience and clarity in explaining intricate details. Simultaneously, I was tasked with analyzing the current approach and proposing enhancements. Beyond the office, I navigated the charming Swiss streets and adapted to the concept of “Ruhetag”(Sundays being completely for Rest), which necessitated planning groceries in advance due to shop closures.</p> <p>The Bern University of Applied Sciences boasted an impressive research infrastructure, complete with robots and cutting-edge machinery. Collaboration among research groups across Europe was common practice, highlighting the importance of a broader perspective in our work. I found myself immersed in a culture of innovation and collaboration that was truly inspiring. Notably, I had the unique opportunity to personally interact with and operate these cutting-edge robots, which encompassed a wide range of functionalities. From robotic arms designed for factory automation to humanoid robots aimed at human-robot collaboration and assisting residents in old age homes, these robots represented the forefront of technology in various applications. These interactions not only enriched my technical knowledge but also underscored the importance of interdisciplinary collaboration in pushing the boundaries of robotics, all within the context of creating positive societal impact.</p> <p>In true Swiss fashion, I immersed myself in the local culture, one of my most memorable memories being embarking on a 12-Km hike with colleagues to a picturesque lakeside church and mountain gorges. These outings not only allowed me better know my colleagues outside the office but to also build strong connections and provide a well-deserved relief from the daily routine. It also provided insights into the beauty of Switzerland’s landscapes, from vineyards to idyllic villages. The Swiss countryside revealed a pristine charm that I had only seen in postcards before.</p> <p>Back in the office, my focus shifted to improving the vision-based pipeline for drones and optimizing image analysis, even under challenging conditions. This project was intellectually stimulating, pushing me to think critically and creatively. The environment fostered a spirit of innovation, and I was fortunate to be part of a team that encouraged exploration and experimentation. What made the challenge even more interesting was that the entire pipeline had to be implemented on a small onboard computer on the drone itself. The task of optimizing the pipeline to operate efficiently on such limited hardware resources was no small feat, and it demanded ingenuity and precision in every aspect of our work. This added layer of complexity truly highlighted the importance of both technical prowess and creativity in finding elegant solutions to real-world problems.</p> <p>Beyond my internship, Switzerland became a launchpad for exploration. I embarked on train journeys across Europe, visiting four countries and accumulating 48 hours of travel time. Switzerland, with its stunning destinations like Lucerne, Mount Pilatus, Zermatt, Geneva, Fribourg, and Zurich, offered a wealth of experiences. Geneva, in particular, felt like a scientific pilgrimage, with a visit to CERN (European Organization for Nuclear Research) being a surreal highlight. The opportunity to visit the epicentre of groundbreaking research in physics left me in awe. My time in Switzerland fostered independence and self-sufficiency, providing a diverse range of experiences that I wouldn’t have encountered otherwise. I learned to navigate the intricacies of daily life in a foreign country, from public transportation to grocery shopping. I also developed valuable life skills, from time management to effective communication in a multicultural environment. These experiences were instrumental in my personal growth and self-discovery.</p> <p>I am immensely grateful to the ThinkSwiss program for this opportunity, which inundated me with knowledge in fields ranging from advanced computer science techniques to valuable life skills, all while making new friends and adapting to life in a new place. It was an adventure of personal and professional growth, a testament to the power of curiosity, adaptability, and the pursuit of innovation in the heart of the Swiss Alps. In conclusion, my Swiss internship experience in 2023 was a transformative journey, a blend of professional enrichment and cultural immersion. Switzerland, with its stunning landscapes, innovative spirit, and warm hospitality, left an indelible mark on my heart and mind. This adventure will forever be a cherished chapter in my life, inspiring me to pursue new horizons and embrace the beauty of diversity and innovation. Switzerland, with its thriving academic and research environment, would surely be on top of my list for further education.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/intern_group_photo-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/intern_group_photo-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/intern_group_photo-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/intern_group_photo.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/swiss_views-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/swiss_views-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/swiss_views-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/swiss_views.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The tasty pizza party after the hike. :yum: and some views during the hike, </div> <p><strong>Signing off…</strong></p> <h5 id="shaurya-kishore-panwar">Shaurya Kishore Panwar</h5> <h5 id="thinkswiss-research-fellow-2023">ThinkSwiss Research Fellow 2023</h5>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="intern-diaries"/><category term="travel"/><category term="work"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Drone Dreams and Swiss Cheese Schemes - My Alpine Internship Adventures]]></summary></entry></feed>