<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://klrshak.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://klrshak.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-05-24T16:16:56+00:00</updated><id>https://klrshak.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Shaurya K. Panwar</title><subtitle>Shaurya Kishore Panwar&apos;s personal website. Collection of personal and professional work and experiences through my career. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Summer Of &apos;69 ’23</title><link href="https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2023/summer-23-intern/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer Of &apos;69 ’23"/><published>2023-08-29T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-29T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2023/summer-23-intern</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://klrshak.github.io/blog/2023/summer-23-intern/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="drone-dreams-and-swiss-cheese-schemes---my-alpine-internship-adventures">Drone Dreams and Swiss Cheese Schemes - My Alpine Internship Adventures</h2> <p>The summer of 2023 marked a pivotal moment in my life as I embarked on an extraordinary journey to Switzerland. My destination: the Computer Perception and Vision Laboratory (CPVR) at Bern University of Applied Sciences, where I would spend my next three transformative months working on the project “No GPS Drone Project” under the guidance of Prof. Marcus Hudritsch. This project aimed to revolutionize drone navigation by developing a purely vision-based system capable of operating in GPS-denied areas and harsh weather conditions.</p> <p>My adventure began with a 5000-kilometer journey from Delhi, India, to Bern, Switzerland. As a final year student at Delhi Technological University, this was my first international experience, and the thrill was palpable. However, one of the initial pleasant surprises was the European summer sunsets, stretching well past 10 PM. Accustomed to the early sunsets of my tropical homeland, this newfound daylight left an indelible mark on my daily routine in my journey. One of my new favourite past times will be exploring the city on my bicycle after work or going for a swim in the lake.</p> <p>The active Swiss lifestyle was soon apparent, especially with my workplace nestled in the foothills of the Jura mountains, requiring a daily uphill hike. Yet, the breathtaking aerial views of the city made every ascent worthwhile. Upon arrival, I was warmly welcomed into a diverse research group, comprising individuals from various corners of the world, all contributing to a vibrant, multicultural environment. Switzerland’s unique linguistic landscape, with my city having both French and German as official languages named Biel/Bienne, added another layer of cultural richness to my experience.</p> <p>My role as an applied research intern commenced with an extensive review of existing work, involving the meticulous examination of over 3000+ lines of code. Thankfully, my colleagues demonstrated exceptional patience and clarity in explaining intricate details. Simultaneously, I was tasked with analyzing the current approach and proposing enhancements. Beyond the office, I navigated the charming Swiss streets and adapted to the concept of “Ruhetag”(Sundays being completely for Rest), which necessitated planning groceries in advance due to shop closures.</p> <p>The Bern University of Applied Sciences boasted an impressive research infrastructure, complete with robots and cutting-edge machinery. Collaboration among research groups across Europe was common practice, highlighting the importance of a broader perspective in our work. I found myself immersed in a culture of innovation and collaboration that was truly inspiring. Notably, I had the unique opportunity to personally interact with and operate these cutting-edge robots, which encompassed a wide range of functionalities. From robotic arms designed for factory automation to humanoid robots aimed at human-robot collaboration and assisting residents in old age homes, these robots represented the forefront of technology in various applications. These interactions not only enriched my technical knowledge but also underscored the importance of interdisciplinary collaboration in pushing the boundaries of robotics, all within the context of creating positive societal impact.</p> <p>In true Swiss fashion, I immersed myself in the local culture, one of my most memorable memories being embarking on a 12-Km hike with colleagues to a picturesque lakeside church and mountain gorges. These outings not only allowed me better know my colleagues outside the office but to also build strong connections and provide a well-deserved relief from the daily routine. It also provided insights into the beauty of Switzerland’s landscapes, from vineyards to idyllic villages. The Swiss countryside revealed a pristine charm that I had only seen in postcards before.</p> <p>Back in the office, my focus shifted to improving the vision-based pipeline for drones and optimizing image analysis, even under challenging conditions. This project was intellectually stimulating, pushing me to think critically and creatively. The environment fostered a spirit of innovation, and I was fortunate to be part of a team that encouraged exploration and experimentation. What made the challenge even more interesting was that the entire pipeline had to be implemented on a small onboard computer on the drone itself. The task of optimizing the pipeline to operate efficiently on such limited hardware resources was no small feat, and it demanded ingenuity and precision in every aspect of our work. This added layer of complexity truly highlighted the importance of both technical prowess and creativity in finding elegant solutions to real-world problems.</p> <p>Beyond my internship, Switzerland became a launchpad for exploration. I embarked on train journeys across Europe, visiting four countries and accumulating 48 hours of travel time. Switzerland, with its stunning destinations like Lucerne, Mount Pilatus, Zermatt, Geneva, Fribourg, and Zurich, offered a wealth of experiences. Geneva, in particular, felt like a scientific pilgrimage, with a visit to CERN (European Organization for Nuclear Research) being a surreal highlight. The opportunity to visit the epicentre of groundbreaking research in physics left me in awe. My time in Switzerland fostered independence and self-sufficiency, providing a diverse range of experiences that I wouldn’t have encountered otherwise. I learned to navigate the intricacies of daily life in a foreign country, from public transportation to grocery shopping. I also developed valuable life skills, from time management to effective communication in a multicultural environment. These experiences were instrumental in my personal growth and self-discovery.</p> <p>I am immensely grateful to the ThinkSwiss program for this opportunity, which inundated me with knowledge in fields ranging from advanced computer science techniques to valuable life skills, all while making new friends and adapting to life in a new place. It was an adventure of personal and professional growth, a testament to the power of curiosity, adaptability, and the pursuit of innovation in the heart of the Swiss Alps. In conclusion, my Swiss internship experience in 2023 was a transformative journey, a blend of professional enrichment and cultural immersion. Switzerland, with its stunning landscapes, innovative spirit, and warm hospitality, left an indelible mark on my heart and mind. This adventure will forever be a cherished chapter in my life, inspiring me to pursue new horizons and embrace the beauty of diversity and innovation. Switzerland, with its thriving academic and research environment, would surely be on top of my list for further education.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/intern_group_photo-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/intern_group_photo-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/intern_group_photo-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/intern_group_photo.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/swiss_views-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/swiss_views-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/swiss_views-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/swiss_views.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The tasty pizza party after the hike. :yum: and some views during the hike, </div> <p><strong>Signing off…</strong></p> <h5 id="shaurya-kishore-panwar">Shaurya Kishore Panwar</h5> <h5 id="thinkswiss-research-fellow-2023">ThinkSwiss Research Fellow 2023</h5>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="intern-diaries"/><category term="travel"/><category term="work"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Drone Dreams and Swiss Cheese Schemes - My Alpine Internship Adventures]]></summary></entry></feed>